Juliette Bruce, Ph.D.

juliette_bruce1@brown.edu https://github.com/juliettebruce www.juliettebruce.xyz +1 (810) 623-7610

PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

I am now excited to apply my mathematical and programming skills to develop software that addresses challenging problems. My research in mathematics brings together computational, combinatorial, and algebraic tools to study the geometry of zero loci of systems of polynomials.

- Co-authored 15 research articles that have been, or are submitted, for publication in top peer-reviewed journals.
- Awarded over \$300,000 in research grants including the extremely competitive NSF Postdoctoral Research Fellowship.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Research Associate

AUG. 2022 - PRESENT

Brown University

Established myself as a leading early-career researcher, with a strong commitment to mentorship and developing cross-field collaborations.

• Served as a member of the Software Presentation Committee for the International Symposium for Symbolic and Computational Algebra.

NSF Postdoctoral Research Fellow

AUG. 2020 - JUL. 2022

University of California, Berkeley

Developed a successful independent research program that brought together ideas from numerous areas of mathematics.

 Mentored several graduate and undergraduate students projects resulting in multiple research articles submitted for publication.

Graduate Assistant

AUG. 2014 - JUL. 2020

University of Wisconsin, Madison

Teaching Assistant for 5 semesters and Research Assistant for 7 semesters the Mathematics Department.

- Developed interactive teaching materials on a weekly basis, and oversaw a team of other TA's as a head TA.
- Received the highest departmental and campus-wide awards for teaching: Capstone Teaching Award (2019) and Teaching Assistant Award for Exceptional Service (2018).
- Received the Excellence in Mathematical Research Award (2019) for significant and substantial contributions to research.

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

BEGINNER HTML/CSS, Pandas, SQL

INTERMEDIATE Python, Matlab

EXPERT Macaulay2, Latex

SELECT PROJECTS

Computational Algebra Packages for Macaulay2

Developed four peer-reviewed software packages extending the functionality of the open-source computer algebra software Macaulay2. These packages are included (or will be included) with the standard distribution of Macaulay2.

Computing Algebraic Invariants

Led a collaborative research project that brought together tools from numerical linear algebra and high throughput computing to develop novel approaches to computing syzygies. Created a website to make the data available to other researchers.

Foundations of AI/ML in Computer Algebra

An ongoing project to develop robust datasets to allow the development of artificial intelligence/machine learning methods in computational algebraic geometry.

SKILLS

Event Organizing

 Organized 10 research conferences ranging from narrowly focused events with 20 participants to large international conferences with over 100 participants.

Technical & Non-Technical Communication

- Gave over 75 invited research presentations at national and international conferences and seminars, including: Harvard, Princeton, Stanford, UC Berkeley, and UT Austin.
- Gave 25 general audience talks aimed at promoting mathematics to the public.

Leadership

- As lead organizer (2016-2018) for the Madison Math Circle, created new programming and community initiatives that increased attendance from 25 to 250 students per year.
- As the inaugural president (2022) for Spectra, the association for LGBTQ+ mathematicians, and oversaw a fundraiser that raised over \$20,000.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2020	Ph.D. in Mathematics
	University of Wisconsin, Madison
2014 - 2016	M.A. in Mathematics
	University of Wisconsin, Madison
2010 – 2014	B.S. in Mathematics & Political Science
	WITH HIGH HONORS & DISTINCTION
	University of Michigan